Preliminary Guide to the Angela M. Jeannet Papers, 1969-1983
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Angela M. Jeannet papers 1969-1983
Jeannet, Angela M.
4.50 linear feet Extent: 1500 Items
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
RL.00632
Language: English.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Angela Jeannet Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2000.
Biographical Note
Co-founder of Lancaster Women's Liberation Group in Lancaster (Lancaster Co.), Pennsylvania.
Collection Overview
Collection documents the activities of one of the earliest local women's liberation groups, started during the second wave of feminism, and co-founded by Jeannet. Included are clippings and a number of publications (volumes, pamphlets, newsletters, and other periodicals) relative to the movement, including newsletters from the Lancaster Women's Liberation Women's Center. Topics discussed include sexual harassment, the Equal Rights Amendment, the pro-choice movement, campus activism, women and work, and the National Organization for Women. Other materials document the inner workings and activities of Jeannet and the group, such as correspondence and meeting minutes. Acquired as part of the Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture.
Subject Headings
Jeannet, Angela M.; Lancaster Women's Liberation Group; Lancaster (Pa.); National Organization for Women; Women's rights; Women's rights -- United States; Feminism; Sexual harassment; Sexual harassment of women; Equal rights amendments -- United States; Women -- Legal status, laws, etc. -- United States; Pro-choice movement; Abortion; Student movements; Students -- Political activity; Women -- Employment -- United States
Preliminary Description of Unprocessed Description
- Accession #2000-0237
  - (Box 1)
  - General Publications (Box 1)
    - Our Past, Our Herstory (Box 1)
    - Women, a Bibliography (Box 1)
    - A Practical Guide to the Women's Movement (Box 1)
    - Political Economy of Women's Liberation (Box 1)
    - Invisible Worker in a Troubled Economy (Box 1)
    - Sexual Harassment on the Job: What You Need to Know (Box 1)
    - Why Not a Woman? Facts about Women and Work (Box 1)
    - Working Woman's Guide to her Job Rights (Box 1)
    - Sisters in Struggle, 1848-1920 (Box 1)
    - Female Liberation as the Basis for Social Revolution (Box 1)
    - Women's Week, March 21- 25 Conference Agenda (Box 1)
    - Guidelines for Feminist Consciousness Raising (Box 1)
  - Lancaster Publications (Box 1)
    - Lancaster Women's Liberation, (newsletter) 1972-1981 (Box 1)
    - Women Will, a publication of Lancaster Women's Liberation, 1981-1983 (Box 1)
    - Lancaster Independent Press, 1970, 1984-1989 (Box 1)
  - Lancaster Women's Liberation (LWL) Records (minutes, etc.) (Box 1)
  - Information Sources (Box 1)
  - Letters (Box 1)
  - LWL Documents (Box 1)
  - Press Clippings (Box 1)
  - 1975 NOW Participant Folder (Box 1)
  - Pennsylvanians for Women's Rights (PWR) (Box 1)
  - WAAW Programs (Box 1)
  - (Box 2)
  - Women and Power (Box 2)
  - ERA (Box 2)
  - Publications (Box 2)
    - Motive: Special double issue on the liberation of women (Box 2)
    - A History of the New Left, 1960-1968 (Box 2)
    - Rise and Fall of Liberal Democracy (Box 2)
    - Chronicle of Higher Education, The Scranton Report: Text of the Findings of the President's Commission on Campus Unrest (Box 2)
    - Training the Woman to Know her Place: The Social Antecedents of Women in the World of Work (Box 2)
    - The Center Magazine (Box 2)
    - Effe: Mensile Femminista Autogestito (Box 2)
    - Quest, Vol 1 No.4, Qualitative Leap Beyond Patriarchal Religion (Box 2)
    - On Integrating the Personal and Political (Box 2)
    - Proposed National Plan of Action, National Women's Conference, Houston, TX, 1977 (Box 2)
    - Abortion: The Right to Choose (Box 2)
    - Time: Special Issue on the American Woman, March 20, 1972 (Box 2)
    - Our Bodies Our Selves, a Course by and for Women (Box 2)
    - Notes from the Third Year: Women's Liberation (Box 2)
    - The Massage Book (Box 2)
    - Physician's Comment Regarding Breast Cancer (Box 2)
    - Women Power (Box 2)
    - Majority Report, 1977 (2 articles on Women's Health) (Box 2)
  - (Box 3)
    - The New Woman's Survival Catalog: A Woman-Made Book (Box 3)
    - Three t-shirts (Box 3)
      - Lancaster Woman's Liberation, Our first decade, (one black, one maroon) (Box 3)
      - Women's Action Committee(WAC): Rescue Choice (Box 3)